<Class>
    <Id>1709</Id>
    <Package>org.apache.derby.impl.store.access.btree.index</Package>
    <ClassName>B2I_v10_2</ClassName>
    <SuperClass>B2I</SuperClass>
    <SuperInterfaceList>
        <SuperInterface></SuperInterface>
    </SuperInterfaceList>
    <ClassComment>B2I_v10_2  /** 
 * Class used to instantiate 10.2 version of the B2I object. This class implements the format of the B2I object as existed in  the 10.2 and previous releases of Derby.  In subsequent releases the format was enhanced to store the Collation Id of the columns in the index.   Collation can be configured on a per column basis to allow for alter sort ordering of each column.  One use of this is to allow a column to be sorted according to language based rules rather than the default numerical ordering of the binary value. For upgrade purpose all columns stored with ACCESS_B2I_V3_ID format are assumed to be USC_BASIC collation id (ie. the default numerical ordering, rather than any alternate collation).   This class reads and writes the V3 version to/from disk and reads/writes current in-memory version of the data structure.
 */
</ClassComment>
    <FieldList/>
    <MethodList>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>B2I_v10_2</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * No arg constructor, required by Formatable.
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType></ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <InnerVarList>
                <InnerVar></InnerVar>
            </InnerVarList>
            <InnerMethodInvokeList>
                <InnerMethodInvoke></InnerMethodInvoke>
            </InnerMethodInvokeList>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getTypeFormatId</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Return my format identifier. &lt;p&gt; This identifier was used for B2I in all Derby versions prior to and including 10.2.  Databases hard upgraded to a version subsequent to 10.2 will write the new format, see B2I.  Databases created in a version subsequent to 10.2 will also write the new formate, see B2I.
 * @see org.apache.derby.iapi.services.io.TypedFormat#getTypeFormatId
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>int</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <InnerVarList>
                <InnerVar></InnerVar>
            </InnerVarList>
            <InnerMethodInvokeList>
                <InnerMethodInvoke></InnerMethodInvoke>
            </InnerMethodInvokeList>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>writeExternal</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Store the stored representation of the column value in the stream. &lt;p&gt; For more detailed description of the format see documentation at top of file.
 * @see java.io.Externalizable#writeExternal
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>void</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList>
                <Parameter>
                    <ParamName>out</ParamName>
                    <ParamType>ObjectOutput</ParamType>
                </Parameter>
            </ParameterList>
            <InnerVarList>
                <InnerVar></InnerVar>
            </InnerVarList>
            <InnerMethodInvokeList>
                <InnerMethodInvoke></InnerMethodInvoke>
            </InnerMethodInvokeList>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType>IOException</ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
    </MethodList>
</Class>