<Class>
    <Id>327</Id>
    <Package>org.apache.derbyTesting.functionTests.util.corruptio</Package>
    <ClassName>CorruptDiskStorageFactory</ClassName>
    <SuperClass>CorruptBaseStorageFactory</SuperClass>
    <SuperInterfaceList>
        <SuperInterface></SuperInterface>
    </SuperInterfaceList>
    <ClassComment>CorruptDiskStorageFactory  /** 
 * This class provides proxy implementation of the StorageFactory interface for testing.  Storage Factory is used by the database engine to access  persistent data and transaction logs. By default all the method calls delegate the work to the real disk storage factory (org.apache.derby.impl.io.DirStorageFactory) based on the classes in the java.io packgs. In some cases this  factory instruments some methods to corrupt the io to simulate disk corruptions for testing. For example to simulate out of order partial writes to disk before the crash.  Derby by default uses the storage factory implementation in  DirStorageFactory/DirStorageFactory4 when a database is accessed with  "jdbc:derby:&lt;databaseName&gt;". This factory can be specified instead using  derby.subSubProtocol.&lt;sub protocol name&gt;  For example: derby.subSubProtocol.csf=org.apache.derbyTesting.functionTests. util.corruptio.CorruptDiskStorageFactory database need to be accessed by specifying the subporotocol name like 'jdbc:derby:csf:wombat'. Interaction between the tests that requires instrumenting the i/o and  this factory is through the flags in CorruptibleIo class. Tests should not  call the methods in this factory directly. Database engine invokes the  methods in this factory, so they can instrumented to do whatever is  required for testing.
 * @version 1.0
 * @see CorruptibleIo
 * @see WritableStorageFactory
 * @see StorageFactory
 */
</ClassComment>
    <FieldList/>
    <MethodList>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getRealStorageFactory</MethodName>
            <MethodComment></MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>WritableStorageFactory</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <InnerVarList>
                <InnerVar>String [dirStorageFactoryClass="org.apache.derby.impl.io.DirStorageFactory"]</InnerVar>
                <InnerVar>WritableStorageFactory [storageFactory=null]</InnerVar>
            </InnerVarList>
            <InnerMethodInvokeList>
                <InnerMethodInvoke></InnerMethodInvoke>
            </InnerMethodInvokeList>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
    </MethodList>
</Class>