<Class>
    <Id>1678</Id>
    <Package>org.apache.derby.impl.jdbc</Package>
    <ClassName>InternalClob</ClassName>
    <SuperClass></SuperClass>
    <SuperInterfaceList>
        <SuperInterface></SuperInterface>
    </SuperInterfaceList>
    <ClassComment>InternalClob  /** 
 * A set of operations available on internal Clob content representations. &lt;p&gt; The methods defined by  {@link java.sql.Clob} must be implemented on top ofthis interface. In addition, there are some methods to aid internal tasks and organization, like transferring one internal Clob representation to another one.
 */
</ClassComment>
    <FieldList/>
    <MethodList>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getCharLength</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Gets the number of characters in the Clob.
 * @return Number of characters in the Clob.
 * @throws IOException if accessing underlying I/O resources fail
 * @throws SQLException if accessing underlying resources fail
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>long</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType>IOException</ExceptionType>
                <ExceptionType>SQLException</ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getCharLengthIfKnown</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Gets the number of characters in the Clob if it is already known. &lt;p&gt; This method will not do any work to obtain the length if it isn't already known. Due to special handling of zero in the code, this method will return  {@code -1} if a length of zero is cached internally.&lt;p&gt; If a positive value is returned, it is expected to be equal to the actual length of the Clob (i.e., no stale values must be returned).
 * @return Number of characters in the Clob, or {@code -1} if the length iscurrently unknown (not cached).
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>long</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getRawByteStream</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Returns a stream serving the raw bytes of the Clob. &lt;p&gt; Note that it is up to the caller of this method to handle the issue of encoding. There is no predetermined encoding associated with this byte stream, it is up to the Clob representation which one it uses. &lt;p&gt; This stream may be an internal store stream, and should not be directly published to the end user (returned through the JDBC API). There are three reasons for this: &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;the stream may be closed by the end user when it is not supposed to&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;operations on the stream might throw exceptions we don't want to present to the end user unwrapped&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;the stream may contain a Derby specific end-of-stream marker &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt; The primary use of this method is to clone the Clob contents without going via char (or String). Make sure the clone uses the same encoding as the original Clob representation.
 * @return A stream of bytes representing the content of the Clob,initialized at byte position 0.
 * @throws IOException if accessing underlying I/O resources fail
 * @throws SQLException if accessing underlying resources fail
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>InputStream</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType>IOException</ExceptionType>
                <ExceptionType>SQLException</ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getReader</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Returns a reader for the Clob content, initialized at the specified character position.
 * @param characterPosition character position. The first character is atposition &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.
 * @return A {@code Reader} serving the content of the Clob.
 * @throws EOFException if the position is larger then the Clob
 * @throws IOException if accessing underlying I/O resources fail
 * @throws SQLException if accessing underlying resources fail
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>Reader</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList>
                <Parameter>
                    <ParamName>characterPosition</ParamName>
                    <ParamType>long</ParamType>
                </Parameter>
            </ParameterList>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType>IOException</ExceptionType>
                <ExceptionType>SQLException</ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getInternalReader</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Returns an internal reader for the Clob content, initialized at the specified character position. &lt;p&gt; This method can return a shared reader object, avoiding instantiation and repositioning costs for internal operations where the stream itself is not published to the end-user. One such example is {@code Clob.getSubString}.
 * @param characterPosition character position. The first character is atposition  {@code 1}.
 * @return A {@code Reader} serving the content of the Clob.
 * @throws EOFException if the position is larger then the Clob
 * @throws IOException if accessing underlying I/O resources fail
 * @throws SQLException if accessing underlying resources fail
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>Reader</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList>
                <Parameter>
                    <ParamName>characterPosition</ParamName>
                    <ParamType>long</ParamType>
                </Parameter>
            </ParameterList>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType>IOException</ExceptionType>
                <ExceptionType>SQLException</ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getUpdateCount</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Returns the update count of the Clob. &lt;p&gt; The update count is increased each time a modification of the Clob content is made.
 * @return Update count, starting at zero.
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>long</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getWriter</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Returns a writer to write data into the Clob. &lt;p&gt; The semantics of the writer is the same as for  {@link #insertString}.
 * @param charPos the starting character position. The first character isat position &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.
 * @return A writer initialized at the specified character position.
 * @throws IOException if writing to the Clob fails
 * @throws SQLException if accessing underlying resources fail
 * @throws UnsupportedOperationException if the Clob representation isread-only
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>Writer</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList>
                <Parameter>
                    <ParamName>charPos</ParamName>
                    <ParamType>long</ParamType>
                </Parameter>
            </ParameterList>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType>IOException</ExceptionType>
                <ExceptionType>SQLException</ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>insertString</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Inserts the given string at the specified character position. &lt;p&gt; The behavior of this method can be defined by the following examples on the Clob &lt;code&gt;clob&lt;/code&gt; with value &lt;code&gt;"ABCDEFG"&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;clob.setString(2, "XX")&lt;/code&gt; - "AXXDEFG" &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;clob.setString(1, "XX")&lt;/code&gt; - "XXCDEFG" &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;clob.setString(8, "XX")&lt;/code&gt; - "ABCDEFGXX" &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;clob.setString(7, "XX")&lt;/code&gt; - "ABCDEFXX" &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;clob.setString(9, "XX")&lt;/code&gt; - throws exception &lt;/ul&gt;
 * @param str the string to insert
 * @param pos the character position the string will be inserted at. Must bebetween &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;clob.length() +1&lt;/code&gt;, inclusive.
 * @return The number of characters inserted.
 * @throws IOException if writing to the I/O resources fail
 * @throws SQLException it the position is invalid
 * @throws IllegalArgumentException if the string is &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;
 * @throws UnsupportedOperationException if the Clob representation isread-only
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>long</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList>
                <Parameter>
                    <ParamName>str</ParamName>
                    <ParamType>String</ParamType>
                </Parameter>
                <Parameter>
                    <ParamName>pos</ParamName>
                    <ParamType>long</ParamType>
                </Parameter>
            </ParameterList>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType>IOException</ExceptionType>
                <ExceptionType>SQLException</ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>isReleased</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Tells if the the Clob has been released. &lt;p&gt; Depending on the context, a Clob is released either because the internal representation has been changed, or because the Clob itself has been closed. The former can happen when a user modifies a stream that is currently represented as a store stream. The latter can happen if {@code Clob.free} has been called, or if Derby implicitly closes theClob.
 * @return {@code true} if released, {@code false} if not.
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>boolean</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>isWritable</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Tells if the Clob representation is intended to be writable. &lt;p&gt; Note that even if this method returns &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;, it might not be possible to write to the Clob. If this happens, it is because the assoicated database is read-only, and the internal Clob representation is unable to obtain the resources it require (could be an area on disk to write temporary data).
 * @return &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; if the Clob is intended to be writable, &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt; if modifying the Clob is definitely not possible.
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>boolean</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>release</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Frees the resources held by the internal Clob representation. &lt;p&gt; After calling this method, all other operations on the Clob will be invalid and throw an exception.
 * @throws IOException if freeing associated I/O resources fails
 * @throws SQLException if freeing associated resources fails
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>void</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType>IOException</ExceptionType>
                <ExceptionType>SQLException</ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>truncate</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * @param newLength the length in characters to truncate to
 * @throws IOException if accessing the underlying I/O resources fails
 * @throws SQLException if accessing underlying resources fail
 * @throws UnsupportedOperationException if the Clob representation isread-only
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>void</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList>
                <Parameter>
                    <ParamName>newLength</ParamName>
                    <ParamType>long</ParamType>
                </Parameter>
            </ParameterList>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType>IOException</ExceptionType>
                <ExceptionType>SQLException</ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
    </MethodList>
</Class>