<Class>
    <Id>3136</Id>
    <Package>org.infinispan.notifications.cachelistener.event</Package>
    <ClassName>CacheEntryModifiedEvent</ClassName>
    <SuperClass></SuperClass>
    <SuperInterfaceList>
        <SuperInterface>CacheEntryEvent</SuperInterface>
        <SuperInterface>K</SuperInterface>
    </SuperInterfaceList>
    <ClassComment>CacheEntryModifiedEvent  /** 
 * This event subtype is passed in to any method annotated with  {@link org.infinispan.notifications.cachelistener.annotation.CacheEntryModified}&lt;p /&gt; The  {@link #getValue()} method's behavior is specific to whether the callback is triggered before or after the eventin question.  For example, if &lt;tt&gt;event.isPre()&lt;/tt&gt; is &lt;tt&gt;true&lt;/tt&gt;, then &lt;tt&gt;event.getValue()&lt;/tt&gt; would return the &lt;i&gt;old&lt;/i&gt; value, prior to modification.  If &lt;tt&gt;event.isPre()&lt;/tt&gt; is &lt;tt&gt;false&lt;/tt&gt;, then &lt;tt&gt;event.getValue()&lt;/tt&gt; would return new &lt;i&gt;new&lt;/i&gt; value.  If the event is creating and inserting a new entry, the old value would be &lt;tt&gt;null&lt;/tt&gt;. &lt;p /&gt;
 * @author Manik Surtani
 * @since 4.0
 */
</ClassComment>
    <FieldList/>
    <MethodList>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>getValue</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Retrieves the value of the entry being modified. &lt;p /&gt;
 * @return the previous or new value of the entry, depending on whether isPre() is true or false.
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>V</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>isCreated</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * Indicates whether the cache entry modification event is the result of the cache entry being created. This method helps determine if the cache entry was created when &lt;tt&gt;event.isPre()&lt;/tt&gt; is &lt;tt&gt;false&lt;/tt&gt;.
 * @return true if the event is the result of the entry being created,otherwise it returns false indicating that the event was the result of a cache entry being updated
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>boolean</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
        <Method>
            <MethodName>isCommandRetried</MethodName>
            <MethodComment>/** 
 * This will be true if the write command that caused this had to be retried again due to a topology change.  This could be a sign that this event has been duplicated or another event was dropped and replaced (eg: ModifiedEvent replaced CreateEvent)
 * @return Whether the command that caused this event was retried
 */
</MethodComment>
            <ReturnType>boolean</ReturnType>
            <ParameterList/>
            <ThrowExceptionList>
                <ExceptionType></ExceptionType>
            </ThrowExceptionList>
        </Method>
    </MethodList>
</Class>